We break the pattern or the pattern breaks us.
It Ends with Us is a drama, romance film directed by Justin Baldoni.
When a woman's first love suddenly reenters her life, her relationship with a charming, but abusive neurosurgeon is
upended, and she realizes she must learn to rely on her own strength to make an impossible choice for her future.
Lily Bloom, played by Blake Lively.
Ryle Kincaid, played by Justin Baldoni.
Allysa, played by Jenny Slate.
Atlas Corrigan, played by Brandon Sklenar.
Marshall, played by Hasan Minhaj.
Andrew Bloom, played by Kevin McKidd.
It Ends with Us is a 2024 American romantic drama film directed by Justin Baldoni and
written by Christy Hall, based on the 2016 novel by Colleen Hoover.
The film stars Blake Lively alongside Baldoni, Brandon
Sklenar, Jenny Slate, and Hasan Minhaj.
The story follows florist Lily Bloom (Lively), whose abusive relationship with neurosurgeon Ryle Kincaid
(Baldoni) is compounded when her ex-boyfriend Atlas Corrigan (Sklenar) re-enters her life.
Principal photography on It Ends with Us took place from mid-2023 to early 2024,
with pauses due to the 2023 WGA strike and the 2023 SAG-AFTRA strike.
It Ends with Us premiered at the AMC Lincoln Square in New York City on August 6, 2024, and
was released in the United States on August 9 by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and was a box-office
success, grossing $351 million against a $25m budget.
The production became mired in controversy due to disputes between Lively and Baldoni, with the former drawing criticism for not addressing the film's
themes of domestic violence and emotional abuse during its promotional tour, as well as using the tour to promote her hair care range.
In December 2024, Lively filed a lawsuit against Baldoni and his production company
Wayfarer Studios, accusing them of sexual harassment and intimidation.
Denying the allegations, Baldoni sued The New York Times for libel over their siding with Lively's account of events, and later sued
Lively, her husband Ryan Reynolds and their publicist Leslie Sloan for civil extortion, defamation, and invasion of privacy.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, love
triangle, abusive father, trauma, florist.
The tone is emotional.